That must be them there
near that big piece of nothing.
According to my G.P. S...
it's about where Texas turns into Oklahoma.
Oh. great. Right in the middle
of a jurisdictional pissing contest.
Look. I'm out of water. Give me yours.
Hey!
Hey! Are y'all F.B. I?
F.B.I. Special Agent Seeley Booth.
This here is Dr. Temperance Brennan
from theJeffersonian.
- Welcome to Oklahoma. ma'am.
- Welcome to Texas. ma'am.
Guys. welcome
to the United States of America.
- Where are the remains. please?
- Oh!
Right here.
Hardly any flesh left.
It's very dry here...
so I'm guessing that time of death
was some months ago.
- How do you think they died?
- They left Oklahoma. hit Texas. then died of despair.
Nope. They're definitely Oklahomans.
If they were from Texas.
they'd have had sense enough to carry water.
That wouldn't show up in the bones.
- No clothing.
- Might've blown away.
Maybe a young couple.
some kind of suicide pact?
Sub-pubic angle suggests two females.
- Oh! Lesbian suicide pact.
- Definitely Texans then.
The victims were pygopagus
or. some would say. illeopagus.
- What's that? - Greek?
- Conjoined twins.
- What's that?
- Siamese twins.
The point of attachment is posterior.
- Ah. joined at the ass.
- Definitely Texans.
So what do we got here. Doc?
Well. it's a federal case. boys.
F.B.I. will take jurisdiction.
Conjoined twin births
occur once every 85.000 births...
the same frequency as hermaphroditic births.
Oh. Mr. Nigel-Murray.
we've so missed your insights.
- Thank you.
- Why weren't the remains dispersed by scavengers?
Well. the depression
in the earth suggested...
that they were buried
in an extremely shallow grave.
The remains were spotted
by an oil survey team from a helicopter.
Begging the question. what exposed the bones?
Well. there was a sandstorm
in that area eight days ago.
Sustained winds of 60 miles an hour.
gusts of about 80.
Third molars have not completely emerged.
and root development is incomplete.
Indicating that the victims
were between 19 and 21 years of age.
Guys. hello.
I.D.'ing them is not going to be a problem.
How many sets of conjoined twins
can there be?
Um. over the last 500 years.
approximately 600 sets...
over 70 percent women.
I did not expect him to know that.
Well. all facts are useful.
It's just the context that shifts.
I bet I couldjust go search
for missing Siamese twins...
and find them in. like. 10 minutes.
- By all means. give it a shot.
- The victims have two separate spinal columns...
fused distally at the lower sacral level.
extending to the pelvis.
No other vertebral anomalies.
Neither one of them could've survived
the death of the other.
So murder/suicide.
suicide/murder or vice versa.
That was vice versa.
Soil beneath the skeletons was full of weirdness.
Quite a bit of decomposed cotton.
- We didn't see any fabric.
- Wow. It was decomposed.
It was fairly cheap stuff too.
I think they were wrapped in a sheet.
Naked. wrapped in a sheet.
Sweets will have something to say about that.
Also. I found soil-dwelling mites-
genus Ameronothrus.
Nearest place they could've picked up
soil mites was hundreds of miles away.
And decomposed popcorn.
They were killed at the movies?
- I have a theory-
- The circus.
Kind of stole my thunder there.
But yeah. Yeah. The traveling circus.
- I found them.
- Already?
- Huh? The circus.
- The circus.
"Abracadabra" was first uttered
to cure hay fever.
Conjoined twins wrapped in a sheet?
- Yep.
- According to Hodgins.
It would help to know
how they were wrapped.
All the evidence is gone with the wind.
- No other clothing?
- According to Hodgins.
The murderer didn't want anyone
to identify them from their clothes.
They're conjoined twins.
You might as well have buried them
with their driver's licenses in their hands.
Wrapped naked bodies often indicate
a careful burial or. of course. sexual assault.
Okay. you know what? That's. uh-
That's creepy. We gotta get going. Sweets.
- Where?
- Texas. That's where the circus is.
Uh. circus folk are extremely
tight-lipped and close-knit.
They won't tell you anything.
- How do you know?
- I-You know. I've read articles.
You're the worst liar I have ever met.
You read articles?
- Even I know he's lying.
- Okay. I'm adopted.
You know-You know what?
My story isn't important here.
No. it's very important. Go ahead.
I-
When I reached the age of majority...
I tried to find my birth mother-
a psychic who worked
the circus-and-carnival circuit in Florida.
- Bio mom was a carny.
- You know what? Let's stay on track.
The point is. no one would talk to me.
- Were you wearing a suit?
- You'll be wearing a suit.
And they won't open up to you either.
I'm just trying to be helpful here.
I suspect Sweets is right.
I studied a carnival for six weeks...
as research
for my cultural anthropology dissertation.
No one would tell me anything...
even though I became
quite adept on the high wire.
Fine. If they're gonna talk to their own.
we will go undercover.
- What?
- If we're joining a circus. we'll need an act.
- I'm quite adept on the high wire.
- No. no. no. You know what?
- We'll have a knife-throwing act.
- Well. I can't throw knives.
I can. I had the best knife skills
in the Rangers.
Are we going to join the circus?
We are gonna join the circus.
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
We're gonna talk to the twins'mother here
in Fort Worth. then pick up our mobile home.
- And we'll join the circus right outside Waco.
- Uh. our mobile home?
Yeah. We're circus folks. Bones.
We crisscross the country in a mobile home.
I had the field office here
paint up something special for us.
Is that all you need
to get a job at the circus- a mobile home?
You know what? It's gonna help.
It's showy. And we're show people.
It's always possible that we'll
talk to the girls' mother...
and solve this whole case tonight.
- Right?
- I hope not.
- What? Huh?
- Hmm?
I should've never let those girls leave this home.
Worst thing that can happen
to a mother. isn't it?
Finding out that you outlived your child.
Unnatural.
Except for societies
with high infant mortality rates.
My understanding is you tried to sue
the circus several times. Mrs. Van Owen.
- It's Mrs. Hicks.
- Dell Hicks here is my husband and my lawyer.
Dell helped me sue the circus for-
Loss of income. alienation of affection...
civil rights abuses.
animal abuses. improper hiring...
emotional distress. mental anguish.
- Any of these go to court?
- It's just a matter of time. Agent Booth.
Hmm. You really hated that circus.
They stole my daughters.
I'll do anything to get back at them for that.
- When did you last see your daughters?
- Four months ago.
- They told us to butt out of their lives.
- Jenny did.
If one of the girls wanted something...
it was the same as both of'em wanting it.
IfJenny wanted something.
then they both wanted it.
Didn't matter whatJulie wanted.
I took a look at the remains...
and I had to wonder if you ever considered
having them surgically separated.
It was too dangerous.
- I disagree.
- So did Jenny and Dr. Muir.
Well. Julie and I thought
it was too dangerous.
Your daughters disagreed
on whether or not they should be separated?
Dr. Muir's office- here in Forth Worth?
I'm sure you understand that my responses
to your questions about the Van Owen sisters...
is somewhat tempered by patient privilege.
They're murder victims. right?
Patient privilege no longer applies.
Well. yes. of course.
I've never- I've never had
a patient murdered before.
You thought that the twins
could safely be separated?
- Yes.
- I agree.
As did Jenny.
ButJulie and her mother disagreed.
She and her...
ambulance-chaser husband tried to sue me.
- So how did you leave things?
- Well. in the end...
it didn't matter what the rest of us thought.
Julie and Jenny were gonna
have to come to an agreement.
I wonder if they thought
they could continue...
to work in the circus if they were separated.
Well. they both loved the circus.
Yeah. Jenny told me once...
that they had some ideas
on how to expand their act.
Sounds likeJenny was the bossy one
and Julie was a little nicer?
Well. they were like any other sisters.
They had distinct
personalities and strengths.
If there's anything else
I can do to help the F.B.I.-
Yeah. Tell you what.
Send the records to the F.B.I.
in Washington.
- Why can't you simply take them with you?
- We have another appointment.
- Thank you for your cooperation.
- Mm-hmm.
The F.B.I. did a wonderful job with this trailer.
Okay. Just lose the Katharine Hepburn voice.
I'm just trying to find my character.
You know. acting.
Well. don't.
It sounds ridiculous. Okay. Bones?
What's my name there. Wanda?
It's written right there
on the side of the truck...
which "high wire" is not.
It's just sometimes you get irritated...
and you say "Booth" without thinking.
I don't do anything without thinking- ever. Buck.
Buck and Wanda and Their Knives of Death. huh?
Never heard of ya.
We've worked the Pacific Northwest.
Canada. Alaska.
I guess that makes you
the beautiful assistant then?
Wanda. Yes.
I'm also quite adept on the high wire.
Well. I gotta admit it would be nice
to have a knife-throwing act around.
Yeah. well. folks. they love a little danger.
- So what's your thing?
- Our thing?
Yeah. Your gimmick.
You know. a cowboy and Indian princess.
A pirate and kidnapped princess.
AJack the Ripper and... princess.
- We're Russian.
- Or the "cowboy and Indian princess" thing.
No. no. no. The Russian thing sounds good.
- It does?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Okay. yeah. We are "Ruska. "
- All right.
Well. you do the first show for free...
and. if I like you. then we talk payment.
Wow.
Uh. you-you ain't seen nothin' yet.
Lavalle!
You two ain't the first of May. are you?
- No. In fact. we are not-
- We are no first of May.
This is Lavalle. He's our 24-hour man.
Lavalle. meet Buck and Wanda Moosejaw.
They do a barber act.
- Moosejaw? What are you- Indian?
- Canadian.
Lavalle will show you where to park
your digs. You can get ready for the show.
- They any good?
- How about that?
Hell. being able to splinter a post
don't make you a showman.
We're show people. all right.
You will be amazed.
Ha!
Russian? You had to pick Russian?
Brilliant. right? It just popped into my head.
Well. you know what? Don't pop things. Bones.
- Sweets. what the hell is "the first of May?"
- A newbie.
A rookie.
Why would a little person
be referred to as a 24-hour man?
Oh. Having a little trouble
with the lingo. huh?
He is the advance person.
He goes to town ahead of the circus
and sets everything up.
If you like. I could e-mail you a lexicon.
- Uh. I would certainly appreciate that.
- Sure.
Um. can I offer a piece of advice?
Well. that's why we called you. Sweets.
Don't try too hard to be their friends.
Act like you're more
interested in each other than any of them.
- All right? They will come to you.
- Okay. Thanks. Sweets.
So. uh. sex. right?
- Oh. Good idea.
- Okay.
Okay. well. I think what we need to do
is get a syncopated rhythm going...
that takes advantage
of the natural frequency of the springs.
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
Are you this spontaneous during real sex?
Yes. I am.
What do you think?
Let's just hope they're as good
outside the trailer as they are in.
I'll give 'em good marks for staying power.
- I don't know what this is.
- I can try to balance it.
- Getting settled in. Moosejaw?
- Yep.
- Nice tent. Very-
- It's a piece of crap.
- Right.
- Let's just pray there's no wind or rain.
I'd hate for it to collapse
on paying customers.
There something we can help you with?
- Aim me at the Van Owen sisters.
- The Van Owen sisters?
Yeah. Sisters. Jugglers. Julie and Jenny.
joined at the hip. literally.
Yeah. funny. How do you know 'em?
They worked a carny up in Alaska
last year. Nice kids.
- Said they were coming down here to work at Bingham's.
- I'm afraid you missed 'em.
Uh. Julie and Jenny. they-they moved on.
Well. when was it. Lavalle?
Uh-After Petersburg. wasn't it?
- Buck!
- Wanda.
Julie and Jenny don't work here anymore.
- Where'd they go?
- Well. you know what?
I think I got a note in here somewhere
from 'em that they left.
"Thanks for everything. We loved working here.
And we love all of you.
"But we've decided to take
another direction in our lives.
You'll always be family.
Love. Julie and Jenny. "
- That doesn't sound like them.
- Well. it sounds likeJulie.
- NotJenny?
- Well. maybe they were forced to leave under duress.
Listen to the five-dollar words
the target can use.
She likes to read the dictionary.
- Tough girl. Jenny.
- Yeah. The rubes sure loved 'em.
Them quitting probably hurt your box office.
Sweetheart. I got nothing
but trouble at the box office.
Yeah. I'm sure we'll run into the girls
somewhere or another.
I mean. there's not many circuses anymore. right?
Food's ready in the mess tent.
If you two can drag yourselves
out of your trailer...
I'll. um. introduce you
to the rest of the gang.
"Duress"? Real smart.
Don't use those kind of words.
- What? Why? Just because I'm in a carnival-
- Oh. forget it.
doesn't mean I can't read books
and have a good vocabular-
Is it more impressive that they
can do that joined at the hip. or less?
Twins die an average of 10 years apart...
even when they are genetically identical.
- Not helpful.
- Ah. X-rays from the twins'doctor in Dallas.
Okay. notice the antemortem bone lesion
in the carpal capitate...
suggesting a stab wound on the hand.
- Did you see the video?
They were juggling machetes.
I found particulates
of magnesium carbonate on both girls.
Do you have any fascinating
trivia on that subject?
- One man's trivia is another man's wisdom.
- Mm-hmm.
It's a chalk- used in flooring. fireproofing.
cosmetics. toothpaste and laxatives.
Obviously. we are on the lookout
for a clean-toothed...
eye shadow-wearing. constipated contractor.
Wow.
Brennan sent a photograph
of the note the twins left at the circus.
How long will it take you to analyze it?
I found something pretty interesting
just by looking at it.
- You said Jenny was the left-handed twin.
- Yes.
Correct. The smudges and the slants
on the letter indicate...
that the note was written
by the left-handed twin.
On a standard keyboard.
there are over 3.000 words...
that can be touch-typed
with the left hand alone.
It's not typed. It's handwritten.
How many can be typed with the right hand?
450. Thank you ever so much for asking me.
- Please don't encourage him.
- Uh-huh.
The point is.
"Jenny" was signed with the right hand...
while "Julie'"signed the note with the left.
This note was obviously
not written by them. guys.
It's fake.
Oh! Look at them. huh? Clowns.
Well. the psychiatric term
for fear of clowns is coulrophobia.
It's not fear. It's hate.
Okay? Big difference.
- You mind?
- Sure. Have a seat.
Buck. Wanda. this is Magnum the Strong Man.
and this is Madam Nina.
- Oh. are those your legal names?
- Is Wanda yours?
Buck and Wanda. they knewJenny and Julie.
- I miss those girls.
- We all do.
- Ah. not the clowns.
- Why is that?
The girls were trying a new act. Borrowed
some of the clowns' equipment without asking.
They should've stuck to juggling.
They werejust trying to help save the circus.
Well. they wanted more time
in front of the audience.
NotJulie. She wanted
to spend more time with her boyfriend.
- Julie had a boyfriend?
- But her sister was literally right beside her all the time.
People can't help who they fall in love with.
When you fall in love with an outsider.
that's the end of circus life.
- Who was it?
- He was a gillie.
- What's a gillie?
- A gillie's an outsider.
So one of the girls had a boyfriend-
Booth. you're sitting on my clothes.
I'm sorry. but it's kind of tight in here.
- Which is why you shouldn't throw your underwear on the floor.
- They fell.
No. Don't blame gravity for lack of tidiness.
- Is there only one bed there?
- Wait. Can we please hit "Rewind"?
- One of the girls had a boyfriend?
- Yes.
Only one of them?
I mean. how do they-
You know. when they're-
I just don't see physically how they-
Okay. look. that's not the issue.
Just take that image out of your mind...
and pretend that they
are separate individuals and ask yourself...
if you found anything
that suggested a relationship.
- Hodgins.
- Huh?
Yeah. Sorry. Still working
on the "mind picture eradication" thing.
Did you find anything
on one of the sisters...
that you didn't find present on the other?
Uh. yeah. Actually. yeah. I did.
Uh. residue of polyelectrolyte polymers under
the fingernails ofJulie and notJenny.
- It's polyvinylpyrrolidone.
- What is that? Makeup?
It's not makeup. It's hair gel.
Seems thatJulie was running her fingers
through someone's hair.
- Julie was the one with the boyfriend?
- Can you identify a brand?
No. But it would smell a lot like sandalwood.
Oh. Smooth Sure Powerhold.
Uh. yeah. that's definitely on the list
of possible products. Yeah.
Dr. Muir was wearing a ton of hair gel.
It smelled just like sandalwood.
What? Son of a barber. okay?
I know my traditional hair products.
SoJulie was having an affair with Dr. Muir?
If we leave now. we can question them
and be back in a couple of hours.
No. Not in this thing.
And we have a show. We can't be late.
You know. we're not circus performers. okay?
We solve murders.
Yeah. We're undercover murder-solvers.
- If we don't make it back in time. we'll blow our cover.
- Tell you what.
I will search for a faster vehicle. all right?
Oh. but first. I gotta go scavenge
some Russian costumes...
because somebody said we did a Russian act.
It was a great idea.
Dr. Brennan. if you do have to perform...
any chance that you could set up
a webcam so we could watch?
You know. to see if we might be of any help
with the case. I mean.
Yeah. Absolutely. Anything to help.
Yes!
- Did you bring our real clothes?
- Yes. They're in the bag.
Where did you learn to drive this thing?
You're kidding me. right? I'm a cop.
We should really talk about our act.
Two complementary fractures
on each of the victims'craniums.
- Like their heads were cracked together?
- Interesting fact.
- Yes. But is it pertinent?
- Indeed.
In the fraternity
of forensic anthropologists...
these are known as "kissing fractures. "
So heads knocked together
is the cause of death?
Little known fact- there were actually
six men known as the Three Stooges.
So we're going with the Three Stooges
as the cause of death?
Such would be my inclination.
I'll let you pass that nugget on
to Dr. Brennan...
when you tell her about the fractures.
I already sent off
the girls' medical records.
I'm not sure how else I can help you.
I want to run my fingers through your hair.
Why?
To prove you were in a sexual relationship
with Julie Van Owen.
And running your fingers
through my hair will prove that?
- Yeah.
- Look Dr. Brennan up on the Internet.
She's getting very famous
for this kind of stuff.
You're not gonna understand this.
- You had a threesome.
- Absolutely not.
I dated Jenny first.
and then I fell in love with Julie.
Jenny didn't really like that.
That's why he recommended
separating the twins.
Well. that's not true.
My recommendation was totally objective.
Maybe the mother found out
and sued his whole life away.
- Which is the only reason we kept the relationship a secret.
- Relationship?
- Sexual relationship?
- How?
Well. when you were-
I'm trying to understand.
- When. uh. you and Julie-
- The girls had separate genitalia.
A fair amount of privacy could be achieved...
by an eye mask
and an MP3 player turned up very loud.
Julie liked the Kings of Leon.
Jenny liked Maroon 5.
The American Medical Association
is going to take away your license.
- Yeah. That's a motive for murder.
- We should arrest him.
Wait. On what charges?
Definitely positive
for the "suspicion of murder" thing.
But you know. the. uh-
The other thing is just. uh-
It's. well. confusing.
Can you go faster? We'll miss the show.
No. We're making great time. Bones.
All right? Relax.
- All right. a little help there.
The phone's ringing.
- I'm kind of busy.
- Oh. okay. Should we talk about our act?
- We need costumes.
- We don't need the Russian costumes. all right?
- We're dropping the act.
- What? You could throw knives. I thought.
Yeah. I know we can.
But we caught the bad guy. all right?
We don't need to go undercover.
What are you doing- digging for loose change?
Oh! Got it.
Special Agent Seeley Booth's phone.
Dr. Temperance Brennan speaking.
Dallas field office. It's for you.
Yeah. of course it is. It's my phone.
- Well. then ask them what they want.
- What is this about. please?
They say that all of Dr. Muir's alibis
checked out...
and they can't hold him for murder.
Whoa. He didn't kill the twins?
He couldn't have driven all the way
to the Texas-Oklahoma border during that time.
Now could we talk about our act?
I do know a few words in Russian.
Oh. no.
Vincent provided me
with the approximate forces it would take...
to cause the kissing fractures
to the twins' skulls.
Approximately 300 pounds
per square inch.
Which is. by the way.
the same as a pit bull's bite.
- Were they attacked by a pit bull?
- Not a likely scenario. no.
See how this works. Mr. Nigel-Murray?
A kind of mental winnowing process.
Okay. scenario number one.
Whiplash.
- No.
- No?
There'd be evidence of trauma
in the vertebrae as well.
- Excellent mental winnowing.
- Okay. scenario number two.
A fall.
No. The rest of the skeleton
would've showed evidence of the fall.
Scenario number three.
They're assaulted separately by a weapon.
That's possible.
- Oh. no. Actually. it's not.
- Why not?
Well. because the wounds are
absolutely symmetrical here.
The possibility of an assailant
striking them separately...
at the exact same angle.
with the exact same force- it ain't gonna happen.
Okay. Well. the heads
could've been conked together.
There'd be evidence
on the soft tissue of the face.
No. There was no soft tissue left.
What if the blunt instrument was soft?
What. like a pillow?
Oh. wait a second.
Clown props.
- I'll call Booth and Dr. Brennan.
- Nice.
When Cortez conquered the Aztecs...
clowns were among the many treasures...
he carried back to Clement VII.
Thank you. That's-
Ah!
- You ready?
- Yes.
Ready to throw knives at beautiful woman.
- Not "at." I hope.
- Right. No. of course.
Ha-ha. Around.
Wow! Wanda. You-You look-
- Wow.
- You too. uh. Boris.
You make beautiful Natasha.
Man. you act like
this is the first time you've done this.
- Yeah. well. we like to keep things fresh.
- So I've seen.
Okay. So. um-
I stand against a board. right.
with balloons all around me...
and then you pop them
with your razor-sharp knives?
Right. Unless we do our actual job
and find the murder weapon.
- What's with the mustache?
- I thought it would add a nice Russian flair.
- It looks like a small animal.
- Too short.
There's a giant plastic ice-cream cone.
a giant plastic shoe...
a giant plastic phone. a giant plastic-
Whoa. whoa. whoa. whoa. whoa!
Mind telling me what you're doing here?
Oh. what. you gonna play tough?
You're clowns. right?
- I throw knives.
- Let's kick his ass.
- Yeah. bring it on. Bozo.
- Uh. we're just looking for a prop. That's all.
Buck here is going to knock
this nose off my face with a knife.
Why does everyone think the clown stuff
is there for everyone?
- This is our stuff.
- Let's kick his ass. you guys.
Traditionally.
clowns are fun loving and anarchistic.
- You are rigid and humorless.
- Let's kick both their asses!
You better have your biggest
ass-kicking shoes on.
Stop!
If y'all want to have a Clem.
that's your business.
But after the show.
- Tumbles. I'm serious.
- Your call.
- All right. Let's go. guys.
- Not so funny now. eh. Tumbles?
That's enough. Moosejaw.
We're lining up.
You two damn well better be ready.
- Thinks he's so big.
- I'm ready. How about you?
- Yeah. I'm ready. Oh. God. Bones.
- Oh! My eye.
- You okay?
- I'm okay.
Well. we can't do the show now.
What? No. The show must go on.
Says who?
Ladies and gentlemen and children of all ages...
welcome to Bingham's Circus of Wonders...
the most sensational. death-defying...
one-ring spectacular on earth!
Here they come! Yea!
Hoo. hoo-hoo-hoo!
Hello. hello!
Hey. hey!
Good day! Good day!
They're clapping for us.
Smile. Boris. and wave.
Show them your knives. Come on.
Where's the Buck Moosejaw I married?
Bonjour. mes amis!
Hey.
- Hey. I got props.
- Props? For what?
Props. Objects for you to throw knives at.
No. no. You are going to stand
against the board- still.
I am gonna throw knives
around you. but not too close.
That does not sound like a very good act.
I'm sure the crowd is expecting
a lot more than that.
There is no act. remember?
There's just me trying not to kill you.
You said you were very good-
trained in knife skills by the military.
Oh. I am very good.
but it's you I am concerned for.
Well. if you say you're skilled. then I have
no reason to doubt you. do I?
You know. it's not good
for the barbers to fight before a show.
Those things are sharp.
Let's just get through this.
all right. Mrs. Moosejaw?
Okay.
Look at that.
The clowns are using those fake barbells.
One of them could've clocked the twins...
and smashed their heads together.
The bar joining the foam weights together.
it's too short.
The fulcrum wouldn't give any of them
sufficient force to cause a kissing fracture.
They're clowns. They have their ways.
Folks. thanks a lot. See you later on.
- You're up.
- And now...
direct from their triumphant tour
of Europe and the Far East...
Bingham's Circus of Wonders
is proud to present the razor-sharp skills...
of the most thrilling.
the most breathtaking...
the most dangerous
knife-throwing act in the world.
Boris and Natasha
and Their Russian Knives of Death!
- Huh. What's up with Brennan's eye?
- Eye patch. That's very rakish.
Plus. she only has to be half as scared.
Bones. just keep your arms
outstretched like this. okay?
- Be very. very still.
- Okay.
- Shouldn't the balloons be closer to my body?
- Not if you want to live.
Waah!
That was amazing! That was really amazing!
- Oh!
- Whoo!
Da! Da!
Natasha's balloons are no match...
for Boris's Knives of Death!
Ah! Da! Hmm.
- Ah!
- Hmm?
Boris. Moya lyubov.
Spare the life of your lyubov.
Da.
Definitely. Da.
Are they sure they know what they're doing?
Oh!
Hey!
You really are as good as you said.
You should try a blindfold.
Says the half-blind woman.
Is it me. or does she seem
a little too into this?
Well. there is. of course.
a sexual component to an act of this sort.
- The knife representing-
- We get it.
Dr. Brennan is showing
remarkable trust and willingness.
Be careful!
She's only got one eye left!
Da! Da!
Well. how about that!
Let's hear it for 'em. folks.
Boris the Brave
and the knee-knockingly lovely Natasha!
Come. Boris.
Let 'em hear it. folks.
They loved us. You were great.
Superb hand-eye coordination there.
Buckie.
- I could've killed you.
- Therein lies the excitement for the spectators.
Our own superstrong Mighty Magnum!
- My God.
- What?
Magnum. Look.
He definitely has the upper-body strength
to swing a foam barbell...
hard enough to cause those fractures.
Check out those arms of steel!
- Hey there. big guy. You got a minute?
- For what?
I want to ask you a question
about my friends. Julie and Jenny.
Look. this is getting old. Now. I told you.
They were here. They left. That's all I know.
Check with some other circuses maybe.
- They're dead. But you knew that. didn't you?
- Dead?
- What are you talking about?
- Their heads were smashed together. weren't they?
- Oh!
- Oh! Geez.
- That guy is strong.
- Well. he is called a "strong man. "
- Well. help me get out of this.
- I'm trying to get out.
Look. I want to put
a BOLO on this guy right away.
Magnum the Strong Man.
Real name- Norman von Gluck.
Well. of course he's big.
He's a strong man.
Look. he's wearing a tank top
that says "Magnum. "
He shouldn't be too hard to spot.
Mr. Nigel-Murray has found
some additional bone anomalies.
- Can you explain?
- "Anomaly." from the Greek anomalos.
I'm thinking we could move
this along a bit faster. Mr. Nigel-Murray.
I found slight longitudinal fractures...
along the distal ends
of all four lower leg bones...
and stress fractures on the cuboids.
Fractures to the lower legs and feet.
Does the guy torture 'em first?
Rubber hose to the feet?
That wouldn't be consistent with the injuries
which are isolated to those specific areas.
Can you send me the X-rays?
- The X-rays are-
- They're on their way.
I was more than capable of telling her that.
I was afraid you'd start talking
about Wilhelm Conrad Röntgen...
and the discovery of the X-ray.
November the 8th. 1895.
He made an image of his wife's hand-
I rest my case.
By the way. we all loved your show.
Oh. thank you. Did you hear the cheering?
- Eh. it was all for me.
- Booth was undeniably good.
However. he's not very imaginative
as far as the act goes.
Look. there is a difference
between imagination and tempting fate.
I am just asking for a little flair.
Flair? You want flair-
- Can I ask about the eye?
- No.
I was thinking
that I could wear a hat of fruit...
and then you could slice
through each fruit while-
Bones. it's over. No more undercover.
The act. it's over.
We have to go question the other performers.
Right.
Hey.
You two want to explain
what happened with Magnum?
- He trapped us in the net.
- For no reason?
- We asked him about the twins.
- Asked what?
Ifhe knew anything about how they died.
- You want us to take care of this?
- Settle.
- Who are you people?
- F.B.I. Special Agent Seeley Booth.
And Dr. Temperance Brennan
of theJeffersonian Institution.
Okay. uh.
the Van Owen twins were murdered.
Our prime suspect right now is Magnum.
He had the requisite strength.
- Magnum never killed anyone.
- People. can you please come back now?
- Tell them to come back.
- None of us are gonna help you.
- Don't you care what happened to the twins?
- You aren't one of us.
You don't get it. do you?
How could you? You're gillies.
No. No. We're not gillies. Our act was good.
Yeah. You're gillies.
- Right.
- We have no case.
Yeah. We will when we bring Magnum in.
We have no definitive forensics
tying him or anyone else to the murder.
You will when you get back to the lab.
You'll find evidence.
The "boneus maximus"
will have his initials on it or something.
I really was pretty good on the high wire.
- I'm gonna try it.
- No- Up there? Now?
Wait a second. Bones. no.
You will-You'll fall. It's too high.
- There's a net.
- You got no depth perception. You have a patch on your eye.
- You won't be able to see.
- No. It's more a case of feel.
- I could do it with my eyes shut.
- You shut your eyes...
and I will shut mine.
'cause I am not watching.
My teacher said I was
one of his best students.
This is crazy.
- Booth. look!
- No.
I told you. I'm not gonna look.
I'm keeping my eyes shut.
This is absolutely- Oh. my God.
Bones. Whoo! Wow! You are fearless.
My feet. I'm not in shape for this.
Look at you. You're doing great.
You think maybe you
could ride a bike on that thing...
and maybe spin a ball on your nose
at the same time?
- Ow! My cuboids.
- Your what?
- The cuboids are the bones in my feet.
- Bones. you all right?
- Bones.
- Yeah. I'm fine.
Oh. my God!
Bones. are you all right?
Yeah. I'm fine.
I know what happened.
- It's pretty obvious. You lost your balance.
- No. To the twins.
They weren't murdered.
The stress fractures
to their fibulas and cuboids?
They were caused by walking on the high wire.
And-And the kissing fracture?
Their heads snapped together
when they fell into the net.
That's why there was no other trauma.
Oh. A conjoined twin high wire act.
Henry said thatJenny wanted to be famous.
Their act would've been completely unique.
Well. that's a first.
Yeah. He covered up an accident
by making it look like a murder.
I didn't kill 'em.
I loved them.
- I would never hurt them.
- We know.
I buried them.
and they needed a proper burial.
Don't say anything. Magnum.
You asked them not to go on the high wire.
but that's exactly what they wanted to do.
It's probably the only thing
Julie and Jenny ever agreed on.
When they dropped to the net. the force
of the fall snapped their heads together.
An accident like that.
their mother definitely would've sued.
The circus would never have survived.
I'm gonna have to arrest you
for interference with a dead body.
- We're sorry. Aren't we?
- Yeah.
- Sorry.
- We're going to get you a good lawyer.
Just don't bring them into this.
'Cause I don't wanna see
the circus die because of me.
What you're gonna have to explain
is why you wrapped 'em in a sheet...
because that's something a woman
would do out of respect.
You'll also have to explain
how you forged their handwriting on a note.
Yeah. I will.
Thanks.
Well. I'll just call up the Dallas field office
and have them pick him up.
Think he'll run again?
No. He won't run.
#Some are reaching. Few are there #
# Want to reign from a hero's chair#
# Some are scared to fly so high #
# Well. this is how we have to try #
# Have no envy and no fear#
# Have no envy #
# And no fear#
- They're gone.
- Yeah.
- We slept through it?
- Yeah. Yeah.
"Boris and Natasha
and Their Russian Knives of Death. "
I guess we all got it in us. huh?
The desire to run off and join the circus.
- We did it.
- Buck and Wanda were damn good.
Buck was more dashing than you. I mean.
Buck drove a motorcycle.
- Well. Wanda was funner than you.
- How?
She let me knock off
a rubber nose from her face with a knife.
You would never let me do that.
You are way too rational.
# Have no envy #
# And no fear#
Where do you think they are now?
Over the horizon.
# When your sister turns to leave #
# Only when she's most in need ##
What's that mean?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org